Register of the Edward Geary Lansdale papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Office Files from the United States Department of Defense, Office of the Secretary of Defense, 1957-1964
  - Subject file
    - Linebarger, Paul M. A., "The Republic of China on Taiwan: A Descriptive Appraisal," World Affairs 126: 1, 1963 Spring
    - Luncheons, 1961-1963
    - Mai Thanh Xuan [see also: Correspondence/Mai Huu Xuan]
    - Malaya, 1963
    - Map briefing, 1959 February 7
    - Mexican Navy Quintet
    - "Military Assistance,", 1959 April 27
    - "Miltary Hardware Catalog," Washington, D.C.: Armed Forces Management, 1963 April (Box 48)
    - Office of Special Operations (OSO)
    - Operational personnel for special duty
    - "The Overseas Image of the United States," memorandum for the Assistant Secretary of Defense, 1958 September 23
    - Patton, George S. (two folders)
    - "The Pentagon," Washington, D.C.: Department of Defense, 1960 April 1
    - Personnel
    - Philippines
      - General
      - Chronological file, 1960-1963
      - "From Palanan to Bataan--A Historical Sketch," Command Conference, volume 1, number 2, undated
      - Huks, 1950
      - Plan for utilization of foreign manpower air units--Philippine Air Section, 1958 December 22
    - Phillips, Rufus
    - Praeger, Frederick A.
    - Proposal for the creation of a World Congress for Freedom and Democracy, 1961 August 22
    - Reader's Digest
    - Report, undated
    - Report, by Hans Heymann and Volney Warner, undated
    - Report, "The Law and the Emergency,", 1965 June 20
    - Reuter, Richard, and CARE
    - Reuter, Richard, and CARE (Box 49)
    - Salazar, Jose Cruz, 1963
    - Smith, Robert Aura
    - "Soviet Treaty Violations," Washington, D.C., Department of Defense, 1959 June 10
    - Special Operations
    - Telegram from Saigon to Secretary of State, concerning composition of South Vietnam Government, 1961 May 29
    - Thailand
    - United States Department of State, Agency for International Development, Community Development, 1961-1962
    - Venezuela, 1963
    - Vietnam
      - General (three folders), 1961-1963
      - Binh Hung ("The Village that Refused to Die")
      - Lansdale's trip, 1961 January
      - Military Assistance Advisory Group (MAAG) materials, 1958, 1960
      - Taylor, General Maxwell D., trip, with Lansdale and party, 1961 October
    - Villamor, Jesus A.
    - Villereal, Cornelio
    - West Germany, Special Forces
- Office Files from the United States Embassy-Saigon, Senior Liaison Office, 1965-1968
  Office files from Lansdale's years as senior liaison officer at the U.S. Embassy in Saigon, including correspondence, day files, memoranda, reports, and subject files, arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - General (Box 50)
    - Miscellany
    - Miscellany, material withheld pending declassification
    - Administrative file
    - Budget, 1966
    - Budget and finances, 1965-1967
    - Efficiency reports (personnel evaluations), 1966-1967
    - Logistics
    - Performance rating report, Lansdale
    - Personnel, 1965-1967
    - Staff list
    - United States Embassy telephone directories, 1967
  - Correspondence
    - General
      - 1965
        - May-August
        - August [cont'd.]
        - September
        - October
        - November
        - December (Box 51)
      - 1966
        - January
        - February
        - March
        - April-May
        - June
        - July
        - August-September
        - October-December
      - 1967
        - January
        - February-March (Box 52)
        - April-May
        - June-July
        - August-September
        - October-December
      - 1968
        - January-February
        - March-April
    - Miscellany, material withheld pending declassification review
    - Official
      - 1965 November - 1966 February
      - 1966 March - 1968 June
    - Telegrams
      - Concerning relations with the press
      - Concerning Premier Nguyen Cao Ky's "One Hundred Days" speech, 1965 September 27-October 9 (Box 53)
    - Weekly reports, 1965 October-November
    - Addiss, Steve, 1965-1966
    - Akin, Cecile, 1966
    - Arundel, Arthur W., 1967
    - Baker, Joseph, 1966-1968
    - Be, Nguyen [see: Nguyen Be]
    - Berg, Alan D., 1967
    - Bohannan, Charles T. R., 1966
    - Bundy, William, 1965
    - Can, Pham Duy [see: Pham Duy Can]
    - Center for Research in Social Systems, 1967
    - Cham, Phan Van [see: Phan Van Cham]
    - Chang, Leonard C. (Chang Lien-Chun), 1967
    - Choate, Charles, 1966-1968
    - Coate, Robert, 1967-1968
    - Connell, William, 1965-1968
    - Deutch, Michael, 1965-1966
    - Dickey, William P., 1965-1967
    - Dupuy, T. N. (Historical Evaluation and Research Organization), 1965-1966
    - Erlandson, Robert, 1967
    - Far East Broadcasting Company, 1965-1967
    - Fishel, Wesley R., 1967
    - Fraleigh, Bert, 1966-1967
    - Fraternity of Phi Gamma Delta, 1966
    - Frivaldo, Juan G., 1968
    - Fulbright, J. W., 1966
    - Gober, Hershel, 1967
    - Hoang Van Lac, 1968
    - Karrick, Samuel, 1966-1968
    - Kissinger, Henry, 1965-1967
    - Kushner, Rose [see also: Subject file/Kushner, Rose], 1966-1967 (Box 54)
      Includes letters by Ellsworth Bunker, B. F. Skinner, Charles Percy, Joseph Tydings, and others.
    - Ky, Nguyen Cao [see: Nguyen Cao Ky]
    - Lac, Hoang Van [see: Hoang Van Lac]
    - Le Phu Nhan, 1966-1967
    - Lodge, Henry Cabot, 1966-1967
    - Marshall, S. L. A., 1966
    - McGrory, Mary, 1965-1966
    - McNamara, Robert S., 1965
    - Mellor, C. R., 1966
    - Melvin, George, 1965-1968
    - Miller, Henry L., 1966-1968
    - Nixon, Richard M., 1965-1967
    - Nguyen Be, 1967
    - Nguyen Cao Ky [see also: Subject file/Nguyen Cao Ky, speech, election seminar], 1966
    - Nguyen Duc Thang [see also: Subject file/Nguyen Duc Thang, General, transcripts of conversations, writings by and about], 1966-1968
    - Nhan, Le Phu [see: Le Phu Nhan]
    - O'Daniel, John W., 1965-1966
    - Pacific Stars and Stripes, 1965-1967
    - Patton, George, 1965-1966
    - Pham Duy Can [see also: Subject file/Pham Duy Can, writings and music], 1966-1967
    - Phan Van Cham, 1967
    - Phillips, Rufus (two folders), 1965-1967
    - Praeger, Frederick A., 1966-1967
    - Redick, Joseph, 1965, 1968
    - Reynolds, Dana, 1965-1966
    - Rioch, David McK., 1967
    - Romney, George, 1965-1966
    - Sharpe, Laurence, 1965-1967
    - Stokely, Dorothy, 1966
    - Thang, Nguyen Duc [see: Nguyen Duc Thang]
    - Thien, Ton That [see: Ton That Thien]
    - Ton That Thien [see also: Subject file/Ton That Thien, writings], 1966-1967
    - Ward, William T., 1965-1966
    - Westmoreland, William C., 1965-1968
    - Williams, Samuel T., 1965-1968
    - Yoh, Bernard, 1966-1968
  - Day file (Box 55)
    - 1965
      - September
      - October
      - November 1-15
      - November 16-30
      - December
    - 1966
      - January
      - February
      - March
      - April (Box 56)
      - May
      - June
      - July
      - August 1-17
      - August 18-31
      - September
      - October
      - November
      - December
    - 1967
      - January
      - February
      - March (Box 57)
      - April
      - May
      - June
      - July
      - August
      - September
      - October
      - November
      - December
    - 1968
      - January
      - February
      - March (Box 58)
      - April
      - May
      - June
    - Informational bulletins and press releases, 1966-1967
  - Memoranda
    - General
    - Miscellany, material withheld pending declassification review
    - Brown, David E., to Lansdale, 1968 June 3
    - Cooke, C. M., Jr., letter, 1968 June 15
    - Ellsberg, Daniel, for the record, 1966 February 26
    - Habib, Phillip, to Lansdale, undated, 1966 October 17
    - Karrick, Samuel
      - For the record, 1966 June-July
      - To Lansdale, 1966-1967
      - To members of the Mission Liaison group, 1965 December 16
      - To Major General Nguyen Duc Thang, 1966 December
      - To Joseph Redick, 1966 April 28
    - Lansdale, Edward G.
      - General (Lansdale to Ambassador and members of Mission Council), 1965-1968
      - For the record, 1965
      - To Ambassador Ellsworth Bunker, 1967-1968
      - To Daniel Ellsberg, 1967 May 10
      - To Phillip Habib, 1966 October
      - To Colonel Joel M. Hollis, 1966 June 6
      - To Ambassador Komer and Wade Lathram, 1967 June 6
      - To Ambassador Henry Cabot Lodge, 1965-1967
      - To Frank McCullock, 1967 April 10
      - To Deputy Ambassador Porter, 1965-1967
      - To "The Old Team" (former Senior Liaison Office staff), 1966-1968 (Box 59)
      - To The Secretary of Defense, 1968 January 17
      - To the Senior Liaison Office, undated, 1966
      - To General Westmoreland, 1965-1966
    - Lathram, L. Wade, to Lansdale, 1967 April 11
    - Lodge, Henry Cabot, to Lansdale, 1965-1967
    - MacDonald, D. G., to Lansdale, 1966-1967
    - Mann, Charles A., to Deputy Ambassador Porter, 1965 December 21
    - Melvin, George, for the record, 1966 March 30
    - Miller, Henry
      - To Lansdale, 1965 October 13
      - To Ambassador William C. Porter, 1966 December 20
    - Phillips, Rufus
      - 1966 April 4
      - To William Connell, 1966 February 23
      - To Vice Presdent Hubert Humphrey (with attachments), 1965, 1968
      - To William Jordan, undated
      - To Ambassador Leonard Unger, 1966 November 10
    - Porter, Deputy Ambassador William J., to Lansdale, 1966-1967
    - Redick, Joseph
      - For the record, 1966 May 12
      - To Executive Officer (reports of Lansdale's meetings), 1966
    - Strong, Berkeley J., for the record, 1966 July 19
    - Valeriano, Napolian, to Lansdale, 1965 November 15
    - Zorthian, Barry, to Lansdale, 1965 December 20
  - Reports and writings
    - "Assigning the Personnel to Vietnam Needed to Win,", undated
    - Hai-Yen (Sea Swallow) special zone, Binh Hung Village, Camao Peninsula, 1966
    - Hoa, Father Loc (of Binh Hung), undated, 1965
    - Lansdale, briefing, pacification effort, for the Secretary of Defense, 1966 November 29
    - Melvin, George, "The Kien Ha Proposal--An Analysis,", 1967 January 13
    - "Moral War Strategy for Vietnam,", 1965 January 19
    - "Nationalist Politics in Vietnam,", 1968 May
    - "Non-Funded Self-Help Projects in the Tay-Ninh Province in 1966,", undated
    - "Notes on Projects,", undated
    - Rural Reconstruction background material (three folders), 1965
    - Rural Reconstruction background material, 1965 (Box 60)
    - Vietnamese slang dictionary, 1966 September
  - Subject file
    - British Advisory Mission, 1962-1963
    - Buddhism
      - Buddhist Church (or Council), writings (in Vietnamese with English translation), 1966-1967
      - Busch, Noel F., "Marxism vs. Buddhism in Southeast Asia,", undated
      - Labin, Suzanne, "Military Coups and Buddhist Affair in Vietnam," Conference Internationale sur la Guerre Politique, circa 1964
    - Bui Quang Trach, "Research Report on the Plain of Reeds,", circa 1967
    - Buu, Nguyen Van [see: Nguyen Van Buu]
    - Can, Pham Duy [see: Pham Duy Can]
    - Coate, Robert, diary from visit to Vietnam, 1967 August-September
    - Critchfield, Richard, undated
    - De Sola Pool, Ithiel, "Political Alternatives to the Viet Cong," draft, 1967 May
    - "Debriefings and Case-Studies Developed at the Far East Training Center," memorandum from Warren L. Ziegler, 1967 February 20
    - "Evaluation of Simulmatics Study on Chieu Hoi," memorandum from Vincent Puritano to James P. Grant, 1968 March 6
    - Foreign Affairs article authored by Lansdale, requests for copies and permission to reprint
    - Hickey, Gerald C., "Accomodation in South Vietnam: The Key to Sociopolitical Solidarity,", undated
    - Huynh Sanh Thong, "Viet Nam Between the Red Devil and the Deep Blue 'C,'" Yale Daily News, February 7, 1966, and publicity and correspondence concerning
    - Joint U.S. Public Affairs Office (JUSPAO) materials
      - Analysis of Saigon newspapers, 1967 May
      - "The Meaning of Some Vietnamese Geographical Names," field memorandum number 41, 1967 October 21
      - "Viet Cong Documentation: Diary of an Infiltrator from North Vietnam," special memorandum number 4, 1966 October
      - "A Vietnamese Looks at TET," field memorandum number 31, 1966 November 28
      - Weekly press summary, 1966 November 6-12
    - Kushner, Rose [see also: Correspondence/Kushner, Rose], 1967
      Includes material relating to civic action projects.
    - Ky, Nguyen Cao [see: Nguyen Cao Ky]
    - Land reform (Box 61)
    - Lathram, Wade L., interview with Charles Von Luttichau, Military Assistance Command-Vietnam Headquarters, 1967 October 20
    - Mai Huu Xuan, General and Chief, Republic of Vietnam Political Warfare Department, address to the Students of the Fifth MAC-V/USOM Sector Advisors Course, 1964 December 14
    - McWirter, Bill, untitled article on General Loan, Saigon, 1966 October 21
    - "Notes on Strategic Hamlets," United States Operations Mission, Office of Rural Affairs, Saigon, 1963
    - Nguyen Cao Ky, speech, election seminar [see also: Correspondence/Nguyen Cao Ky], undated
    - Nguyen Duc Thang, General, transcripts of conversations, writings by and about [see also: Correspondence/Nguyen Duc Thang], 1965-1967
    - Nguyen Van Buu, imprisonment and trial, 1966-1983
      - Office of Civil Operations (OCO)
      - Office of the Deputy Director, day file, 1966-1967
      - "A Summary of Vietnam's New Constitution," OCO notice number 67-92, 1967 May 2
    - Pacification (Rural Reconstruction), general
    - Pham Duy Can, writings and music
    - Phillips, Rufus, writings, 1964, 1968
    - Press leaks
    - Radio Hanoi, intercepted broadcasts, 1966 March 17 and September 25
    - Recorded tapes, transcripts [see also: SOUND RECORDINGS]
    - "Selected Officials of Provinces, Districts, and Autonomous cities of South Viet Nam (as of October 30, 1965),", undated
    - Silver, Solomon, "Counter-Insurgency and Nation Building: A Study with Emphasis on Southeast Asia,", 1967 September 25
    - Thang, Nguyen Duc [see: Nguyen Duc Thang] (Box 62)
    - Thien, Ton That [see: Ton That Thien]
    - Thong, Huynh Sanh [see: Huynh Sanh Thong]
    - Ton That Thien, writings [see also: Correspondence/Ton That Thien]
    - United States Agency for International Development (USAID)
      - "Communique from Executive Committee of the Dalat Forces Struggling for Democracy," memorandum from T. E. Naughten, 1966 May 24
      - Letter and mimeograph copy of "The Development and Resources Corporation's Contribution to the Joint Development Group's Report,", 1967
      - Soldier's bond to purchase food, National Liberation Front, with attached memorandum
    - United States Department of State
      - General, printed matter, 1966
      - "Politics and Victory in South Viet Nam," memorandum, 1965 August 3
      - Report A-781, 1968 August 13
    - United States Military Assistance Command, Vietnam (MACV)
      - Briefing, "Enemy Order of Battle,", undated
      - "Command Information Topic Number 5-65, Vietnamese TET," memorandum, 1965 December 7
      - "Organizations and Functions for Civil Operations and Revolutionary Development Support [CORDS]," directive number 10-12, 1967 May 28
    - "U.S. Press Playbacks,", 1965-1966
    - Vietnam War, unidentified and undated papers
    - Vietnamese elections
      - Constituent Assembly
        - 1966 July-August 19
        - 1966 July 20-September
      - National, 1967
    - Vietnamese language, folklore, religion
    - Vietnamese national government, political parties
    - Vietnamese village government
    - Wofford, Dan, "Final Report: Hoi Chanh Group Motivation and Possible Use of Group Dynamics as an Instrument of Government Reform,", 1966 August 18-September 21
    - Xuan, Mai Huu [see: Mai Huu Xuan]
- Oversize Materials, 1947-1975
  Newspapers, scrapbooks, memorial albums, and other oversize material, arranged by form.
  - Miscellany (Box 63)
  - Cambodian newspaper, La Depeche du Cambodge, Phnom Penh, 1965 August 30, 31
  - Philippine newspapers, 1947-1968
    - The Daily Mirror, Manila, 1954 January 17
    - The Daily Pacifican, Western Pacific (Army), special on Manila, 1948 March 14 and October 15
    - The Evening News, Manila, clipping, 1947 November 28
    - The Eye, Manila, 1957 October 5 and 1959 March 14
    - The Fookian Times, Manila, 1948 August 21
    - The Manila Chronicle, clippings, 1947 November 5
    - The Manila Times, 1948 September 8, 1949 February 4, 1953 April 3 and 1968 August 14
    - The Manila Tribune, 1949 November 6
    - The News Behind the News, Manila, 1957 October 4
    - The Philippine Flyer, Manila, 1956 June 22
    - The Philippine Free Press, Manila, and special, 1954 June 5 and 1958 August 9
    - The Pioneer Herald, Dagupan City, 1948 May 21
    - The Star Herald, Manila, 1948 September 4
  - United States newspapers and magazines
    - Clippings, articles on Angolan guerrillas, The Washington Post, 1973 December 23-26
    - Clippings and magazines, Magsaysay campaign, 1953
    - Clippings and tear sheets, Vietnamese conflict, 1961-1975 (Box 64)
    - Potomac magazine, 1972 December 10
  - Venezuelan newspapers and publications
    - Clarin, Caracas, 1963 March 14
    - The Daily Journal, Caracas, 1963 March 13 and 15
    - Guerrilla leaflet, undated
  - Vietnamese newspapers and tear sheets
    - Saigon Daily News, 1966 March 19
    - Thoi The, Saigon (in Vietnamese with English translation), 1967 March 26
    - The Times of Vietnam, Saigon (magazine section), 1958 August 6 and 1959 February 4
    - Vietnam Courier, Hanoi (special issues) and numbers 36-38, 1965 September 2 and 23, October 7 and 21
  - Ting Sing Wu, Taiwan the Beautiful, Hong Kong: the International Culture Press (in Chinese and English), 1960 (Box 65)
  - Ngo Dinh Diem, album in honor of [see also: SUBJECT FILE/Vietnam/Ngo Dinh Diem], 1954 July 7 - 1956 July 7
  - Sketch of Lansdale (inscription: "Feather Merchant")
  - Scrapbook, "To Colonel Edward Lansdale, 'Feather Merchant' and salesman-extraordinary of democracy," from the Free Philippines staff, Manila, 1953 November 17
  - Scrapbook, 18 pages of clippings and 32 letters regarding In the Midst of Wars, 1972
  - Twenty loose clippings and 36 letters regarding In the Midst of Wars, 1972
  - United States Philippines Ryukyus Command, headquarters staff directory (chart), 1948 August 11 (Box 66)
  - United States Agency for International Development, chart, undated
  - The "World Declaration of Independence," folder containing display, undated
- Printed Matter (Boxes 67-68)
  Scope and Content note
  Newspaper clippings, magazines and periodicals, books, reprints, and other printed matter, arranged alphabetically by title.
- Photographs, 1913-1980; 3410 prints, 629 duplicates, 57 proof sheets, 172 negatives and negative strips, 4 slides, 11 albums / 237 envelopes, 5 folio boxes, 2 slide boxes.
  - 29 unidentified prints, undated (Envelope A)
  - 6 prints (with 5 duplicates), 1 proof sheet and 2 negatives of Lansdale service portraits, 1943-1965 (Envelope B-C)
  - 6 prints (with 2 duplicates) and one oversize print of Lansdale alone, in uniform, 1943-1965 (Envelope D-mE)
  - 23 prints of Lansdale alone, 1943-1968 (Envelope F-J)
  - 3 prints of Lansdale addressing a graduating class at the U.S. Army Civil Affairs School, Fort Gordon, Georgia, 1960 November 1 (Envelope K)
  - 2 prints of Lansdale at a Christmas banquet, circa 1943-1944 (Envelope L)
  - 7 prints and 2 oversize duplicates of Lansdale on "Meet the Press," Vietnam, undated (Envelope M-mN)
  - 7 prints of Lansdale receiving awards, 1948, 1958 (Envelope O-Q)
  - 4 prints (with 26 duplicates) of Lansdale receiving award from Vice President Richard Nixon; also pictured are General Nathan Twining and Secretary of Defense Charles Wilson, circa 1955-1957 (Envelope R-S)
  - 5 prints (with 6 duplicates) of Lansdale receiving Distinguished Service Medal; also pictured are General Nathan Twining, Mr. Allen Dulles (Director, C.I.A), and Lt. General Charles P. Cabell (Deputy Director, C.I.A.), 1957 January 8 and 1963 October 31 (Envelope T)
  - 1 print (with 1 duplicate) of Lansdale and friends celebrating his promotion to Brigadier General, 1960 May 5 (Envelope U)
  - 4 prints (with 4 duplicates) of Lansdale visiting a temple, undated (Envelope V)
  - 2 prints of Lansdale with friends, Denver, 1949 (Envelope W)
  - 14 prints of Lansdale with General J. Lawton Collins, disembarking from airplane, and meeting with Vietnamese officials and Buddhist leaders, undated (Envelope X)
  - 12 prints of Lansdale with Ambassador Henry Cabot Lodge and General William C. Westmoreland, at meeting, undated (Envelope Y)
  - 1 print of Lansdale with Admiral William Alexander Sutherland, Jr., National War College, undated (Envelope Z)
  - 2 prints of Lansdale with Nguyen Duc Thang, Minister of Rural Reconstruction, Vietnam, circa 1965-1968 (Envelope AA)
  - 2 prints of Lansdale with friends in the Philippines, 1945 (Envelope AB)
  - 1 print of Lansdale with Academic Instructor class, circa 1949 (Envelope AC)
  - 25 prints of Lansdale with unidentified others, Philippines and Vietnam, 1945-1968 (Envelope AD-AF)
  - 1 oversize print of Lansdale with unidentified others, Philippines, 1950-1954 (Envelope mAG)
  - 123 prints (with 22 duplicates) of Lansdale's friends, Philippines, 1944-1954 (Envelope AH-AN)
  - 25 prints (with 5 duplicates) depicting "despodidas" for Lansdale (with notable guests including Philippine President Ramon Magsaysay), Philippines, 1952, 1954 (Envelope AO-AP)
  - 5 prints of a dinner party given by Colonel and Mrs. Tellman at the joint U.S. Military Advisory Group (JUSMAG) compound, Manila, undated (Envelope AQ)
  - 50 prints (with 30 duplicates) of various social gatherings, Philippines, circa 1950-1954 (Envelope AR-AV)
  - 1 album containing 42 prints depicting various events, people and places in the Philippines, 1947-1948 (Envelope fAW)
  - 47 prints (with 28 duplicates and 16 enlargements) of a "barrio fiesta" attended by Ngo Dinh Nhu and Mme Nhu, Saigon, 1956 (Envelope AX-BA)
  - 1 slide of Lansdale at a ceremony, undated (Envelope BB)
  - 38 prints (with 21 duplicates) of the wedding of Trinh Minh Nhut, son of the late Cao Dai General Trinh Minh The, Vietnam, 1967 (Envelope BC-mBF)
  - 1 album containing 47 prints of the wedding of Trinh Minh Nhut, Vietnam, 1967 (Envelope fBG)
  - 1 print of Ambassador Ellsworth Bunker, with Lansdale in background, Vietnam, 1967 (Envelope BH)
  - 9 prints depicting the Burma Armed Forces engaged in military civic activities, 1959 (Envelope BI-BJ)
  - 1 print of a memorial to Dickey Chapelle, Hai Yen, Vietnam, undated (Envelope BK)
  - 2 prints of Father Raymond De Jaegher with Chiang Kai-Shek and with Lansdale in group (with 1 duplicate), 1956 (Envelope BL)
  - 9 prints of President Dwight D. Eisenhower during a trip to Okinawa, circa 1955 (Envelope BM)
  - 1 print of the Freedom Studies Center in Boston, Virginia, aerial view, undated (Envelope BN)
  - 1 print of Colonel A. G. Gabriel, after receiving award; 1 print of Col. Grunwell receiving award, undated (Envelope BO)
  - 3 color slides depicting Japanese countryside, undated (Envelope BP)
  - 8 prints depicting Tokyo, Japan after World War II, undated (Envelope BQ)
  - 10 prints of meetings at the Joint U.S. Military Assistance Group (JUSMAG) compound in Manila, 1950-1954 (Envelope BR)
  - 2 prints of Lieutenant Edward R. Lansdale, Jr. receiving awards, undated (Envelope BS)
  - 5 prints depicting the Laos Armed Forces engaged in military civic activities, 1959 (Envelope BT)
  - 22 miscellaneous prints from the Philippines, undated (Envelope BU-BV)
  - 19 prints of the Philippine countryside, undated (Envelope BW)